Su Zhang

Software Engineer

CONTACT ME

1 0451 991 558

suzhang79@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/su-zhang-au

https://github.com/coderGirlSu

https://codergirlsu.dev/

Sydney

EDUCATION

Computer Science

Standford Online 2023

Diploma of Information Technology

Coder Academy 2022

Bachelor of Architecture

Harbin Institute of Technology 2010 - 2013

STRENGTHS

- Full Stack Web App Development
- Backend Development
- · Self Learning
- Problem solving
- AWS fundamental services
- Fluent in Mandarin

SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Golang, Ruby, Python, Node.js, HTML, CSS.
- **Frameworks:** React, Ruby on Rails ,gRPC, Rest, Jest
- Software: VSCode, Figma, SourceTree, AutoCAD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Buildkite, Backstage, Kubernetes, Git, GitHub, Trello, Heroku, Firebase, Agile Board, Postman, XMind, Balsamiq, draw.io

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack software engineer with one year of experience. As a certified AWS practitioner with a firm grasp of Computer Science, I am passionate about building things and solving problems, especially using generative AI technologies such as LLMs and diffusion models.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Engineer Intern

2022-2023

SafetyCulture

- Developed full-stack team projects in a microservice architecture that involved many different technologies, such as React, Typescript, Golang and Temporal workflow.
- Worked on a project to integrate the <u>Boston Dynamics Spot robot</u> image and temperature data sensors with the SafetyCulture application.

Graphic designer

2019-2021

Access Displays & Digital Printing Pty Ltd

- Developed designs to meet client requirements using industrystandard design tools, including Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Collaborated with a team of designers, clients and printing companies to create high-quality products and websites

Buildings Architect

2011-2018

Harbin University of Science and Technology

- Drew and designed architectural construction plans and architectural renderings that met client requirements and building regulations using AutoCAD, 3ds Max and SketchUp.
- Communicated with clients to determine planning project requirements and provide updates accordingly.
- Coordinated the design team to ensure aspects such as structural support, water, and electricity arrangements are coordinated throughout the project.

ACHIEVEMENTS

AWS Cloud Practitioner Certificate

2023

Credentials:

https://www.credly.com/badges/4519b7fc-ecbe-419c-8d2c-948bd3cafd34/public_url

- Successfully obtained the AWS Cloud Practitioner certification in 2023, demonstrating a strong foundation in cloud computing principles and AWS services
- Proficient in core AWS cloud concepts, including cloud architecture, security, and billing, along with a deep understanding of fundamental AWS services and their use cases
- Skilled in managing AWS cloud infrastructure, including virtual servers (EC2), storage (S3), and databases (RDS), ensuring optimal performance and cost-efficiency
- Well-versed in cloud best practices, enabling the design and implementation of scalable, reliable, and secure AWS solutions that meet business objectives and compliance requirements.

KEY PROJECTS

Robotic data capture - Boston Dynamics Spot

- Created an innovative solution using the Boston Dynamics Spot robot at SafetyCulture that involved robotics programming to independently navigate a predetermined path, capturing high-quality photos and measuring temperature using infrared sensors.
- Utilised the data collected to conduct comprehensive inspections, integrating with the SafetyCulture platform to provide valuable
 insights into safety and maintenance requirements, thereby automating tasks that were previously time-consuming, dangerous,
 and error-prone.
- Leveraged API development skills to upload media to inspection devices used by SafetyCulture customers for more efficient and accurate inspections, enabling seamless access to valuable findings.

OpenAI - Personal writing assistant tool

- Built a personal assistant tool using Golang that leverages AI technology from OpenAI's APIs and integrates into MacOS using Apple shortcuts.
- · Features include translating text, enhancing writing, and grammar-checking using the GPT-4 model.
- **GitHub**: https://github.com/coderGirlSu/translate-tool

Temporal - Data governance workflow

- Implemented Data Governance functionality utilising technologies and tools, including Figma, React, TypeScript, gRPC, Go, and Temporal Workflow.
- · Developed an intuitive and user-friendly interface for managing data using Figma, React, and TypeScript.
- Utilised gRPC and Go to create a fast and reliable backend for the feature.
- Integrated Temporal Workflow to efficiently manage complex workflows and ensure the smooth running of the feature.
- Presented the Data Governance feature to a large audience of over 150 engineers within the engineering department.
- Demonstrated exceptional technical expertise and dedication in the successful implementation of the feature.

MERN stack - Chat App

- Spearheaded the development of a feature-rich MERN stack chat application in collaboration with a team of two.
- Incorporated advanced features such as user authentication, group creation and chat rooms, chat history viewing, adding friends, dark mode, and custom Halloween theme to provide an enhanced user experience.
- Employed Express for advanced backend features and deployed the application on AWS EC2 instances.
- · Leveraged Firebase authentication and MongoDB Atlas for efficient database management.
- Utilised React for front-end development and deployed on Netlify for ease of use.
- · Ensured the chat software has scalability and provides a solid foundation for future feature development.
- App website: https://tiktalk.codergirlsu.dev/
- GitHub: https://github.com/coderGirlSu/TikTalk-server

Hackathon - React Emoji Search App

- Built an app to search emojis in a four-person team in one and a half days
- Used ReactJS, JavaScript, CSS and HTML including a YouTube presentation and documentation
- Includes features such as search, click-to-copy emoji, pop-up toast notifications, dark mode and team photos
- · Collaboration with team using GitHub fork workflow and PRs
- · Deployed on Netlify
- App website: https://emojis.codergirlsu.dev/
- YouTube presentation: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tTJmHlxH-fo
- GitHub: https://github.com/coderGirlSu/coder-academy-hackathon-team-why-not

Ruby on Rails - Marketplace

- Created a two-sided marketplace with the following features:
 - File upload capabilities, user authentication, messaging, search, sorting and filtering capabilities
- · Developed using Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL, and deployed to Heroku
- **Github:** https://github.com/coderGirlSu/SuZhang_T2A2